# Philip Bulsink

MSc., BSc.,

www.chemcalculator.com in /in/bulsinkp **y** pbulsink pbulsink

## Summary

A master's educated chemist with 2+ years experience programming with Python and R. Searching for an opportunity to pivot my career into a programming or data role, capitalizing upon proven analytical skills, award winning collaboration, and comfort in multi-faceted projects.

## Languages

Python	Advanced	Including Flask, Django, numpy, scipy, and matplotlib.
R	Advanced	Assorted projects available on Github.
<b>LATEX</b>	Advanced	Master's thesis & resumé written in LaTEX, available on Github.
HTML	Intermediate	Some HTML in support of full stack work with Django/Flask.
*nix bash	Intermediate	Utilized bash scripts in MSc. degree on computing cluster.
SQL	Basic	Some experience with SQL gathered while using programming APIs.

## Experience

2014-Present Fuels Chemist, Characterization Lab, Natural Resources Canada, Ottawa.

Perform method development and analysis of research fuels using modern instrumental techniques.

Detailed achievements:

- o Collaborate with internal and external clients to develop and evaluate international standards for testing of pyrolysis oils.
- Maintain compliance with ISO9001:2000 quality control standards, including:
  - Management of an active repository of current test operating instructions
  - Development and maintenance of control charting software

2015-present **Developer**, *EJPHC*, Ottawa, part-time.

Full stack development (in Python/Django) of a yet-unreleased online tool for Edward Jenner Public Health Consultants, Ltd. Utilizing test driven development practices, continuous integration, and version control.

2013–present **Developer**, chemcalculator.com, part-time.

Full development (in Python/Flask) and maintenance of online tools to simplify calculations common in chemical or physics labs.

2010-2011

Research Assistant (Co-op), DeNO<sub>x</sub> Group, Natural Resources Canada, Ottawa.

Research of catalysts for cleaning diesel engine emissions. Custom built instrumentation and analysis software for studies.

#### Education

- 2012–2015 Masters in Chemistry, University of Ottawa.
  - thesis Exploring the Chemistry of Re<sup>(1)</sup>: Physical and Theoretical Investigations
- supervisors Dr. Darrin Richeson & Dr. Tom Woo
- description Laboratory based synthesis and characterization of novel photocatalysts. The mechanism of reaction is studied with the help of new Python tools on a large computing cluster
- 2007–2012 Honours Chemistry, Co-op, Music Minor, University of Waterloo.

#### Honours and Distinctions

2011–2014	Dean's Honour Roll	University of Waterloo, University of Ottawa
2014	Teaching Assistant Award of Excellence	University of Ottawa
2013	Graduate Student Poster Award	Canadian Society of Chemistry
2012	Collaboration Award	CanmetENERGY. Natural Resources Canada

### Select Publications

- Bulsink, P. "Exploring the Chemistry of Re<sup>(I)</sup>: Physical and Theoretical Investigations" University of Ottawa Thesis 2015
- o Stanciulescu, M., Bulsink, P., Caravaggio, G., Nossova, L., Burich, R. "NH3-TPD-MS study of Ce effect on the surface of Mn- or Fe-exchanged zeolites for selective catalytic reduction of NOx by ammonia", *App. Surface Sci.*, 300, pp. 201-207, 2014
- Bulsink, P., Korobkov, I., Woo, T., Richeson, D. "Transforming the chemistry of Rel to access the Elusive Pincer Geometry", CSC Inorganic Division Poster Symposium, 2013
- Stanciulescu, M., Caravaggio, G., Dobri, A., Moir, J., Burich, R., Charland, J.-P.,
  Bulsink, P. "Low-temperature selective catalytic reduction of NOx with NH3 over
  Mn-containing catalysts", App. Catal. B: Env., 123-124, pp. 229-240, 2012.

#### Volunteer Activities

2015-present Chair, Outreach Committee, Calvin Christian Reformed Church, Ottawa.

Chair of outreach committee, promoting internal and external events and initiatives. Introduced program to discern needs of local community, in partnership with other local organizations. Member of church Board of Directors.

2014–2015 Chair, Transitional Team, Calvin Christian Reformed Church, Ottawa.

Chaired committee leading discussions and assisting acting pastors through transitioning to new lead pastor. Hosted open forums, guided discussions and submitted recommendations to Board of Directors.

2013–present **Co-Founder, Director**, *Giving Refugees Hope in Uganda*, Ottawa.

Co-founder and director of local charity supporting refugees in Kampala, Uganda. Organize fundraisers, administer projects, designed & built website.